Working Inventory of the Robert E. Marshak Papers, 1947-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- Box J1
  - CESSE-APS, including: (Box-folder J1-11)
    - Correspondence concerning the need for APS assistance to the National Coalition for Science & Techology; the goals and objectives for the National Coalition, etc.
  - APS (Chinese Project), including: (Box-folder J1-12)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: Harry Lusting, Treasurer of the American Physical Society.
    - 2. APS Magazine, May 1992.
    - 3. APS China Program final report, 1983-1991.
- Box J2
  - APS Committees, including: (Box-folder J2-1)
    - 1. Correspondence on committee memberships.
    - 2. Correspondence on Committee on Minorities.
    - 3. Correspondence on nominating committees.
    - 4. Announcements of prize winners.
    - 5. Phone list of prize committee members.
    - 6. Correspondence on Salary Committee.
  - APS-Committee on International Freedom of Scientists (CIFS), including: (Box-folder J2-2)
    - Correspondence to/from: Andrew M. Sessler, Pascal Schirato, etc.
  - APS-Communication on public education. (Box-folder J2-3)
  - Congressional Fellowship Program, including: (Box-folder J2-4)
    - Correspondence to/from members.
  - Consortium of Affiliates for International Programs (CAIP), including: (Box-folder J2-5)
    - Correspondence from Joseph Burton.
  - Constitutions and bylaws. (Box-folder J2-6)
  - Corson Report, Scientific Freedom, including: (Box-folder J2-7)
    - 1. Articles.
    - 2. Correspondence to Dale Corson, David A. Wilson.
  - CSSP-Concern and Issues of Our Societies talk by Marshak, 1983. (Box-folder J2-8)
  - APS Council Meeting, including: 1983. (Box-folder J2-9)
    - List of motions and actions during the meeting.
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, including: (Box-folder J2-11)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: E. L. Goldwasser, A. Wattenbuerg, Carl M. York.
    - 2. Meeting minutes.
  - Division of Particles and Fields (DPF), including: (Box-folder J2-11)
    - Correspondence and papers concerning the Chicago DPF Meeting, 1970.
  - APS Development: Correspondence. (Box-folder J2-12)
  - Directed Energy Weapons (DEW) Report, including: (Box-folder J2-13)
    - AIP news releases; APS press releases; correspondence; articles; APS study.
  - DPF Correspondence. (Box-folder J2-14)
  - Correspondence to/from Mildred S. Dresselhaus. (Box-folder J2-15)
  - Copies of APS Email Correspondence. (Box-folder J2-16)
  - APS Executive Committee, including: (Box-folder J2-17)
    - Listing of 1983 officers; agenda for 1984 meeting, etc.
  - APS European Physical Society (EPS), including: (Box-folder J2-18)
    - Correspondence to/from Jacques Friedel, J. A. Burton, etc.
- Box K1
  - APS Fellowship Committee/Correspondence re: nominations for the APS. (Box-folder K1-1)
  - Correspondence re: forums on Physics and Society. (Box-folder K1-2)
  - Correspondence to/from W. Havens. (Box-folder K1-3)
  - High School Panel, including: (Box-folder K1-4)
    - Articles, reports, correspondence dealing with the crisis in Science and Technology education.
  - Institute for Theoretical Physics, including: (Box-folder K1-5)
    - Mailing list for the advisory board; suggested candidates for nomination; etc.
  - Bylaws and correspondence from the International Physics Group. (Box-folder K1-6)
  - APS/IUPAP, including: (Box-folder K1-7)
    - Correspondence fromW. Havens to APS Council concerning the IUPAP 1987 General Assembly.
  - Latin America, including: (Box-folder K1-8)
    - Pan American Symposium on Particles and Technology; AAAS Western Hemisphere Cooperation Project and Intercience Association; tentative proposals.
  - Correspondence to/from D. Lazarus, including: (Box-folder K1-9)
    - Correspondence concerning the Publications Committee.
  - Correspondence to/from J. Lebowitz. (Box-folder K1-10)
  - Correspondence concerning various meetings. (Box-folder K1-11)
  - Correspondence concerning the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC). (Box-folder K1-12)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Box-folder K1-13)
  - Nuclear Arms Control, including: (Box-folder K1-14)
    - Weinberger's Address to Virginia Tech on Founder's Day, 1986.
    - Draft of the Science and Technology of Directed Energy Weapons.
  - Nuclear Arms Control, including: (Box-folder K1-15)
    - Correspondence re: study.
  - APS Officers/Correspondence from Neal Lane. (Box-folder K1-16)
  - Personal correspondence to/from: J. A. Burton, W. Havens, etc. (Box-folder K1-17)
  - Reports concerning the physics budget. (Box-folder K1-18)
  - Correspondence to/from Jan S. Nilsson, J. A. Burton, etc., re: Physics in Development (PID). (Box-folder K1-19)
  - Correspondence from J. A. Burton re: Baddeck Workshop. (Box-folder K1-20)
  - Correspondence re: Pork Barrel Peer Review. (Box-folder K1-21)
- Box K2
  - Correspondence re: APS and the Panel on Public Affairs. (Box-folder K2-1)
  - Correspondence and proposals. (Box-folder K2-2)
  - APS Protests, including: (Box-folder K2-3)
    - Correspondence to/from/about Piccioni.
  - APS Public Relations. (Box-folder K2-4)
  - Articles and papers related to retiring President of the APS. (Box-folder K2-5)
  - Correspondence with Abdus Salam. (Box-folder K2-6)
  - APS Subcommitee on International Scientific Affairs (SISA), including: (Box-folder K2-7)
    - Correspondence concerning the group and other issues.
  - APS Topical Groups, including: (Box-folder K2-8)
    - Correspondence re; Scientific Freedom (editorial) in Physics Today, Jan. '84.
  - APS Seminars, including: (Box-folder K2-9)
    - Plans for future activities.
  - Correspondence of the APS Toll Committee. (Box-folder K2-10)
  - Trieste Conference, including: (Box-folder K2-11)
    - List of lecturers; approval for travel requests; correspondence.
  - Washington Office/APS Office of Public Affairs, including: (Box-folder K2-12)
    - Reports; correspondence from Robert Part.
- Box L1
  - A-Correspondence; Notes from meeting with T. Keith Glennan. (Box-folder L1-1)
  - B-Correspondence to/from: Raymond N. Ball, Shirley Brignall, etc. (Box-folder L1-2)
  - C-Correspondence, including: (Box-folder L1-3)
    - 1. Chairman's reports, papers, etc.
    - 2. Class roster.
  - Correspondence; Council meetings. (Box-folder L1-4)
  - College of Arts and Sciences-Meetings and Reports 1969-1970. (Box-folder L1-5)
  - Computing Center at the University of Rochester, including: (Box-folder L1-6)
    - Details on services for the month's ending.
  - Correspondence on Contracts and Grants. (Box-folder L1-7)
  - Listing of the Library Committee. (Box-folder L1-8)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, including: (Box-folder L1-9)
    - Proposal for the development of a new class of scanning photometer; projects for 1980.
  - Correspondence to Members of the Committee of Name Professors. (Box-folder L1-10)
  - DuBridge Symposium, 1984. (Box-folder L1-11)
  - Correspondence from: J. B. French, S. Okubo, J. Rosen, etc. (Box-folder L1-12)
- Box L2
  - E-Correspondence. (Box-folder L2-1)
    - Including correspondence to/from: A. Ecksteing, J. Eden, G. Emch.
  - Correspondence to/from Eastman Kodak Company. (Box-folder L2-2)
  - F- Correspondence. (Box-folder L2-3)
    - Including correspondence to/from: F. Fairbanks, G. Ford.
  - Faculty Senate Correspondence. (Box-folder L2-4)
  - G-Correspondence. (Box-folder L2-5)
    - 1. Including correspondence to/from: D. Gilbert, L. Gillman
    - 2. Geology Department.
    - 3. General Electric (GE).
  - H-Correspondence. (Box-folder L2-6)
    - Including correspondence to/from: H. Hanson, J. Hoffmeister.
  - High Energy Physics Information Exchange (HEPIE). (Box-folder L2-6)
    - Including correspondence to/from: E. Lofgren, H. Wolfe.
  - Honorary Degree Committee. (Box-folder L2-7)
    - Correspondence concerning nominations for the Honorary Degree recipient from Alfred Harris.
  - I-Correspondence (Empty). (Box-folder L2-8)
  - Inter-Unversity Committee on Travel Grants. (Box-folder L2-9)
    - Including correspondence to/from: W. Wallis, L. Mitchel. Also, Annual Reports for '64-'65 and '62-'63.
  - J-Correspondence (Empty). (Box-folder L2-10)
  - K-Correspondence. (Box-folder L2-11)
    - Including correspondence to/from: Morton Kaplon.
  - L-Correspondence. (Box-folder L2-12)
    - Including correspondence to/from: Martin Lessen, E. Lofgren, Sol. Linowitz.
  - M-Correspondence. (Box-folder L2-13)
    - Including Math Department correspondence to/from: Robert Anderson, J. Kemperman.
    - Including correspondence to/from: D. McLeod, David McBride.
  - N-Correspondence. (Box-folder L2-14)
    - Including correspondence to/from: Albert Noyes, B. Nigam, H. Nussenzvief.
    - News releases from 1955-1956.
  - National Academy of Sciences (NAS). (Box-folder L2-15)
    - Including correspondence to/from: Henry Faul, Wallace Atwood, Walter Gleason.
  - O-Correspondence. (Box-folder L2-16)
    - Including correspondence to/from: S. Okubo.
  - P-Correspondence. (Box-folder L2-17)
    - Including correspondence to/from: S. Potter and Donald Parry.
  - Preceptorial. (Box-folder L2-18)
    - 1. Schedules.
    - 2. Correspondence and report, "A Proposal for Arms Control and Disarmament."
  - Dr. Bernard Peters Correspondence. (Box-folder L2-19)
  - HET Group Left Publications. (Box-folder L2-20)
    - Including publications by: C. Hagen, V. Mathus, Y. Liu.
  - Publications Group Left. (Box-folder L2-21)
    - Names of the publication group.
  - Q-Correspondence (Empty). (Box-folder L2-22)
  - R-Correspondence. (Box-folder L2-23)
    - 1. Including correspondence to/from: A. Ravin, F. Reichsman.
    - 2. Rochester Gas & Electric Corporation correspondence to/from: R. Kraybill, R. Kruger.
    - 3. Correspondence concerning the 4th Annual Insitute of International Affairs.
    - 4. Correspondence concerning the Rochester Museum.
  - Reports. (Box-folder L2-24)
    - Including the "Report of the Committee on Recreuitment by Outside Agencies."
  - Reports. (Box-folder L2-25)
    - Including "Priviliged Preliminay Statistical Data from the Study of Postdoctoral Education in the United States" and "Graduate Study in Physics."
  - Reports. (Box-folder L2-26)
    - Including "Migration of Scientists from Latin America: Causes and Possible Solutions."
- Box M1
  - Letters of Recommendation for/Correspondence with
    - T. Becherrawy. (Box-folder M1-1)
    - Dr. Giordano Bisiacchi. (Box-folder M1-2)
    - Dr. R. Chanda. (Box-folder M1-3)
    - J. Chen. (Box-folder M1-4)
    - S. Cohen. (Box-folder M1-5)
    - Dr. J. A. Cronin. (Box-folder M1-6)
    - Dr. Peter Cziffra. (Box-folder M1-7)
    - T. Das. (Box-folder M1-8)
    - Dr. Ezio Ferrari. (Box-folder M1-9)
    - Dr. H. Goldberg. (Box-folder M1-10)
    - Graduate Students. (Box-folder M1-11)
    - M. Grynberg. (Box-folder M1-12)
    - G. S. Grunalnik. (Box-folder M1-13)
    - Dr. C. R. Hagen. (Box-folder M1-14)
    - John P. Holden. (Box-folder M1-15)
    - J. P. Hzu. (Box-folder M1-16)
    - Dr. Afzaal Hussain. (Box-folder M1-17)
    - M. Kaplon. (Box-folder M1-18)
    - Dr. M. P. Khanna. (Box-folder M1-19)
    - Dr. T. W. B. Kibble. (Box-folder M1-20)
    - K. Kikkawa. (Box-folder M1-21)
    - Ick Joh Kim. (Box-folder M1-22)
    - Jean Marc Levy-Leblond. (Box-folder M1-23)
    - Yu-Chien Liu. (Box-folder M1-24)
    - K. T. Mahanthappa. (Box-folder M1-25)
    - A. K. Mohanti. (Box-folder M1-26)
    - A. J. Martin. (Box-folder M1-27)
    - Dr. V. S. Mathur. (Box-folder M1-28)
    - W. J. Meggs. (Box-folder M1-29)
    - Dr. Rabindra N. Mohapatra. (Box-folder M1-30)
    - Michael J. Moravcsik. (Box-folder M1-31)
    - D. A. Nutbrown. (Box-folder M1-32)
    - Dr. S. Obuko. (Box-folder M1-33)
    - Dr. P. Olesen. (Box-folder M1-34)
    - Yuri Orlov. (Box-folder M1-35)
    - Dr. L. K. Pandit. (Box-folder M1-36)
    - Dr. J. Pasupathy. (Box-folder M1-37)
    - Publications Group. (Box-folder M1-38)
    - Dr. M. Rashid. (Box-folder M1-39)
    - Dr. Riazuddin. (Box-folder M1-40)
    - Dr. C. P. Ryan. (Box-folder M1-41)
    - M. Samuel. (Box-folder M1-42)
    - M. P. Savedoff. (Box-folder M1-43)
    - Salvatore Serio. (Box-folder M1-44)
    - Hugo Strubbe. (Box-folder M1-45)
    - Dr. Robert L. Thews. (Box-folder M1-46)
    - Dr. P. Thrunauer. (Box-folder M1-47)
    - Dr. Y. Ueda. (Box-folder M1-48)
    - Dr. Arvind Vaidya. (Box-folder M1-49)
    - Dr. T. C. Yang. (Box-folder M1-50)
    - Y. Yang. (Box-folder M1-51)
  - Review of papers. (Box-folder M1-52)
  - Copies of the Rochester Review (1960, 1962, 1966, 1968); Final reports of the Senate Committee on the Administration of Graduate Studies. (Box-folder M1-53)
  - Seminar Distribution List, 1969-70; Theoretical Particle Physics Group. (Box-folder M1-54)
  - Alumni Relations. (Box-folder M1-55)
    - Including correspondence from: Donald E. Smith, R. James Shoup.
  - University of Rochester, including: (Box-folder M1-56)
    - Explanation of operating costs.
    - Supplementary information on High Energy Program.
    - Notes.
    - Listing of those with a Ph.D. in High Energy Theory.
- Box M2
  - S-Correspondence, including: (Box-folder M2-1)
    - 1. Faculty Scholarship Fund: agenda (1966); list of contributions; correspondence from Catherine Bartholomew.
    - 2. Sherwood Project (1959): correspondence to/from Harry Harrison, Clifton T. MacLeod; contract for research at University of Rochester.
  - Science Development Committee, including: (Box-folder M2-2)
    - 1. Space Science Center correspondence from R. S. Knox.
    - 2. Space Science Center Advisory Committee meeting minutes.
  - Seminars and Lectures, including: (Box-folder M2-3)
    - First two Pulsar Seminars (1969); seminar notes, reports, etc.
  - By-laws and Senate Charter. (Box-folder M2-4)
  - Communications on Improvement in Teaching. (Box-folder M2-5)
  - Communications on student-University Relations. (Box-folder M2-6)
  - Communications on contracts and grants. (Box-folder M2-7)
  - Communication on recruitment. (Box-folder M2-8)
  - Communication on student residences. (Box-folder M2-9)
  - Communication on faculty benefits. (Box-folder M2-10)
  - Communication on University-community relations. (Box-folder M2-11)
  - Correspondence concerning academic affairs. (Box-folder M2-12)
  - Communication on cultural climates. (Box-folder M2-13)
  - Research policy and external grants. (Box-folder M2-14)
  - Research policy communications. (Box-folder M2-15)
  - Newspaper articles. (Box-folder M2-16)
  - Senate information. (Box-notebook M2-1)
  - Sigma Xi, including: (Box-folder M2-17)
    - Correspondence from William Aldridge; nominations for membership; list of nominees.
  - State Atomic Committee, including: (Box-folder M2-18)
    - Subcommittee listings; correspondence.
  - State Advisory Council to the Legislature, including: (Box-folder M2-19)
    - Correspondence; agenda from first meeting; notebook with biographies of Science Advisory.
  - Campaign Steering Committee, including: (Box-folder M2-20)
    - Minutes to the meeting (1967); information from meetings.
  - Minutes of the Senate, 1964-1969. (Box-folder M2-21)
  - Steering Committee Minutes. (Box-folder M2-22)
  - Ravin Report: Report of the Student-Faculty Committee. (Box-folder M2-23)
  - Senate Committee-Listing of newly elected senators, senate subcommittees. (Box-folder M2-24)
  - Correspondence with Patrick Parker. (Box-folder M2-25)
- Box N1
  - Certificate from the Anglo-American-Hellenic Bureau of Education (Box-item 1)
  - Correspondence from Robert L. Sproull and others; reports and letters to the Senate Steering Committee. (Box-folder N1-1)
  - Steering Committee: agendas; minutes of meetings; correspondence to Faculty Senate. (Box-folder N1-2)
  - Travel expense materials, including.: (Box-folder N1-3)
    - Requests for approval of foreign travel.
    - Travel expenses to the Trieste International Symposium.
    - Correspondence concerning travel.
  - Teaching activity materials, including (Box-folder N1-4)
    - Correspondence concerning CV and publications lists.
    - Student course opinion questionnaire.
    - Paper on graduate study in phyics, 1968.
  - Telescope project, including: (Box-folder N1-5)
    - Proposal for a 60-inch Metal Mirror Telescope for the Mees Observatory.
    - Notes for the Telescope project.
  - Correspondence to/from University of Rochester President, Allen Valentine. (Box-folder N1-6)
  - W-Correspondence. (Box-folder N1-7)
    - Including correspondence to/from: Bryon B. Williams, W. D. Walker.
  - Robert E. Marshak (REM) Personal. (Box-folder N1-8)
    - Including; newspaper clippings, articles by/about REM, papers.
  - REM. (Box-folder N1-9)
    - Including: Correspondence concerning 1967 trip to Belgrade, Yugoslavia.
  - REM Personal. (Box-folder N1-10)
    - Including: personal correspondence.
  - REM. (Box-folder N1-11)
    - Including: reports and papers by REM, correspondence.
  - Memoirs. (Box-folder N1-12)
    - Including: articles written by REM, correspondence to REM, other memoirs.
  - Victor Weisskopf. (Box-folder N1-13)
    - Including: Copy of correspondence from Weisskopf to Albert Einstein (1948); correspondence from REM and S. A. Goudsmit to Weisskopf.
  - Photography Department. (Box-folder N1-14)
    - Including: correspondence concerning photography and exhibit proposals, magazine Camera (1963).
  - Personal correspondence to REM; registration and accomodation files. (Box-folder N1-15)
  - REM Personal. (Box-folder N1-16)
    - Including: correspondence from 1976, articles.
  - REM Physics Symposium, January 21-22, 1977. (Box-folder N1-17)
    - Including: correspondence.
- Box N2
  - Memoirs-NEH Grant, including: (Box-folder N2-1)
    - Microfilm of memoir, memoirs as President of City College.
    - Correspondence; list of addresses.
  - REM Personel, including: (Box-folder N2-2)
    - Biographical data on REM.
    - Correspondence from N. Michael Carfora.
  - REM Personal, including: (Box-folder N2-3)
    - Correspondence to/from: Austin M. Gleeson, Katsumi Tanaka.
  - REM Personal, including: (Box-folder N2-4)
    - Newspaper article re: new position at VPI.
  - REM Personal, including correspondence. (Box-folder N2-5)
  - REM Personal Data, including: (Box-folder N2-6)
    - Letter of resignation to University of Rochester, 1970.
    - Resume, list of publications.
    - Correspondence of congradulations.
- Box O1
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), including: (Box-folder O1-1)
  - Atoms for Peace Awards: finanacial statements, programs, and nominations (1957, 1959). (Box-folder O1-2)
  - Atoms for Peace: correspondence and notes. (Box-folder O1-3)
  - Atoms for Peace Awards: correspondence. (Box-folder O1-4)
  - Atoms for Peace Awards-Advisory Committee on Nominations, 1959-1960. (Box-folder O1-5)
  - Atoms for Peace Awards-Advisory Committee on Nominations, 1958-1959. (Box-folder O1-6)
  - Atoms for Peace Awards-Advisory Committee on Nominations, 1957-1958. (Box-folder O1-7)
  - Atoms for Peace Awards, 1960-1961. (Box-folder O1-8)
  - International Foundation for Science adn Technology (IFS): correspondence. (Box-folder O1-9)
  - Atoms for Peace Awards, 1960-1961. (Box-folder O1-10)
  - Correspondence concerning the ISF to/from: C. Yang, M. Paic. (Box-folder O1-11)
  - ISF Correspondence, reports, and notes, 1970-1971. (Box-folder O1-12)
  - ISF Correspondence, reports, and notes, 1972-1973. (Box-folder O1-13)
- Box O2
  - The Royal Society-International Foundation for Science. (Box-notebook O2-1)
  - Office of Technology Assessment (OTA), including: (Box-folder O2-1)
    - Report: OTA Priorities for 1979.
    - Correspondence from Joseph Coates.
  - Nigeria: Workshop, Meeting notes, Working documents (1979). (Box-folder O2-2)
  - International Organization Affairs, including: (Box-folder O2-3)
    - Correspondence to/from Charles William Maynes.
    - Papers by Cyril D. Tyson, Moyibi Amoda, and Beverly Elizabeth (Jewish-Black Relations: Aggressive Monologues of the Two Victim Group).
  - International Foundation for Science (IFS), including: (Box-folder O2-4)
    - Correspondence to/from Nicolai Herlofson, Sven Brohult.
    - Minutes to meetings.
  - IFS Annual Report, 1977. (Box-folder O2-5)
  - Correspondence, including: (Box-folder O2-6)
    - Claudia B. Alston, Harland Cleveland.
  - IFS, 1977-1978. (Box-folder O2-7)
    - Article by W. Murray Todd.
    - Correspondence from Abdus Salam, Joseph L. Birman.
  - IFS, 1974-1975. (Box-folder O2-8)
    - Budget proposal for 1974.
    - Invited participants and board meeting agenda.
    - Correspondence from Roger Revelle, Michael Greene.
  - IFS, including: (Box-folder O2-9)
    - Correspondence from W. Murray Todd.
  - Correspondence to/from W. Murray Todd; Proposals. (Box-folder O2-10)
  - IFS, including: (Box-folder O2-11)
    - Papers on research grants.
- Box P1
  - Science and Technology, including: (Box-folder P1-1)
    - Paper and reports: Solar Energy and the Third World by Norman L. Brown; The Management and Control of Technology by Keith Pavitt.
  - University Committee on International Programs (UCIP), including: (Box-folder P1-2)
    - Correspondence from Robert Dyck.
    - Position paper on Faculty Exchange and Leave Policies.
  - U.S.-Japan Committee, including: (Box-folder P1-3)
    - NSF/Tokyo reports for 1970.
    - Proposal for research.
  - U.S.-Japan Committee, including: (Box-folder P1-4)
    - NSF/Tokyo reports for 1971, 1972.
    - Proposals for fellowship, research work.
    - Report on the status of U.S.-Japan Cooperative Science Program, 1971.
  - U.S.-Japan Committee on Scientific Cooperation, Ninth Meeting, Tokyo, July 7-10, 1969. (Box-notebook P1-1)
  - Office of the Foreign Secretary. (Box-notebook P1-2)
  - Proceedings of a Conference: A National Policy for Urban America, 1976. (Box-notebook P1-3)
  - National Academy of Science (NAS), including: (Box-folder P1-5)
    - NAS Correspondence, 1958-1959.
    - Report on Soviet Union trip, 1963.
    - Correspondence related to work on nuclear forces at Rochester.
- Box P2
  - NAS Files, including: (Box-folder P2-1)
    - Centennial program, 1963.
    - Correspondence to/from: E. C. Rowan, Mary Ryan.
    - Article by Philip Handler.
    - Listing for doctorate graduates at City College, 1963.
  - NAS Files, including: (Box-folder P2-2)
    - Papers concerning changes in minutes.
    - Correspondence from Allen V. Astin, E. C. Rowan.
  - NAS Files, including: (Box-folder P2-3)
    - Correspondence to/from: Adolph Y. Wilburn.
    - Prograom for 1971.
  - Annual Report of the Foreign Affairs. (Box-folder P2-4)
  - Advisory Committee on International Organization and Programs (ACIOP), including: (Box-folder P2-4)
  - ACIOP Meeting, Septempber 1971. (Box-folder P2-5)
  - ACIOP Subcommitee on Science in UNESCO March 1972. (Box-folder P2-6)
- Box Q1
  - Correspondence to/from: Frances Hightower, James A. Shannon, Aaron Rosenthal. (Box-folder Q1-1)
  - Independence de Charge on Physique Nucleaire, including: (Box-folder Q1-2)
    - Correspondence from Harrison Brown, Ralph W. Taylor.
    - Proposals for a symposium on Soviet Science, 1965.
  - Consequences of Chance Independence for the Magnetic Moments and Masses of E. Hypersons, including: (Box-folder Q1-3)
    - Correspondence to/from: John D. Lynn, III, Marcel Bouisset, Harrison Brown.
    - Scientific notes; parts of Yugoslav monthly magazine, 1964.
  - Harrison Brown: notes on draft agreement; reports on scientific exchanges (1962, 1964). (Box-folder Q1-4)
  - Phenomenological Two-Nucleon Potential up to 150 Mev., including: (Box-folder Q1-5)
    - Correspondence to/from: Martin J. King, Lawrence B. Buttenwieser, Richard W. Tims.
  - Present States of the Meson Theory of Nuclear Forces, including: (Box-folder Q1-6)
    - Correspondence to/from: Harrison Brown, Conyears Herring.